qantara.de 2019-09-15

# | Qantara.de - Dialogue with the Islamic World

**Data collection and logging**

Each time one of the websites of Qantara.de and the data on it is accessed, a log file is created and saved with the following information:

  * name of the file or data accessed
  * date and time of access
  * the amount of data transferred
  * confirmation on whether the data was accessed successfully
  * IP-address (unique address for internet-ready devices)
  * referrer (name of the website accessed immediately before)
  * browser name (including version)
  * Operating system used

We log the traffic on Qantara.de for data security reasons and to ensure the stability and reliability of our system while also protecting Qantara.de against possible external attacks. In addition to this, we evaluate the data using statistical analysis. The data kept in the log file are not directly linked to users and their identities, and are for internal purposes only. They are not passed on to third parties. The data is not be used to personally identify visitors to our websites. The data is not collated or merged with any other data. The administration of our websites using information technology as well as anonymous statistical surveys based on data usage allow for a better overall evaluation of the data accessed on Qantara.de in order to optimise our online offerings (see below).

**Personal data**

You can obviously use the content on Qantara.de without disclosing any personal data. Personal data means information that could be used to disclose your identity such as your name, your email address and country.

In certain individual cases (for example competitions, newsletters, blogs or communities), we do, however, need to use personal data. In such cases we will expressly draw your attention to this and will, on principle, kindly ask for your consent to collect and process your personal data. See also our terms of use for further information. When we collect, process and use such personal data, we always do so only for the stated purpose. The data will be treated confidentially, stored on secure servers and will not be forwarded to third parties or used for other purposes.

You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time with immediate effect. If you have any questions, please contact the Qantara.de Data Protection Officer.

**Your rights (relating to revocation, correction and deletion of information)**

Your data will only be used for the stated purposes and will not be sold to anyone. You have the right to revoke your consent at any time. You can direct such requests to us using the contact details on this website. Please note that if you should choose to revoke you consent to access your data, personalised services on Qantara.de may, however, no longer be available.

You have the right, as stipulated in EU legislation, to demand information about what personal data (such as your name and address) is stored on Qantara.de. Please submit such requests in writing to the Qantara.de Data Protection Officer  and state what subject your data disclosure request is in reference to.

In accordance with the statutory provisions, you also have the right to have your personal data corrected and deleted. Please submit such requests to us using the contact details on this website.

**Contact forms and confidentiality of emails**

We offer contact forms in many places on Qantara.de. We will use your data shared on such contact forms for the specified purposes. Should other purposes also be applicable we would explicitly point this out and ask for your consent in such cases. Please also note the following if you send us any emails: we cannot guarantee the confidential treatment of your correspondence on its way to us if you choose to use an unencrypted email service provider.

**Use of cookies**

**What are cookies?**

Cookies are small text files that are temporarily stored on the hard disk of your device. Qantara.de uses cookies for technical reasons without pointing this out in detail on each occasion. We save your IP address during the use of cookies.

Cookies do not store any personal data, and are used to collect anonymous data and statistics on the use of the website by visitors. Cookies help us measure how well our websites are performing. This data helps us to improve and customise our content so you get more out of your visit to Qantara.de.

**Which cookies does Qantara.de use?**

_Session cookies_

These cookies only last for the duration of a session. They will disappear from your computer when you close the browser or turn your computer off. If you have chosen to identify yourself on Qantara.de, we will also use session cookies that contain encrypted information to identify you.

_Persistent cookies_

These cookies remain on your computer even after you close the browser or turn off the device. They are activated each time a user visits the website that created that particular cookie. To this end, you are assigned a unique identifier. This unique identifier is part of a persistent cookie that we leave on your browser. This serves various purposes such as, for example, saving your preferred Qantara.de language.

If you do not want us to remember your computer, you can disable the storage of cookies in the browser that you are using or turn on notification for when cookies are sent.

Qantara.de can also be used without cookies.

Cookies remain active for 365 days. Post-click cookies (which are necessary to track data after the initial click) is set to 20 days by default.

**Measurement and analysis tools (in development)**

We employ usage data for statistical purposes and analyses to help us to constantly improve and develop our online content. We do not aggregate the collected data with other data sources. The data is used for internal purposes only and not disclosed to third parties.

The apps that are currently distributed by Qantara.de are designed to serve the purpose of data economy. For statistical evaluation purposes, we collect information on when and how often the apps are started, used, closed and updated. This information is analysed as individual pieces of data and not linked to any other data. No personal data is used during the data analysis process. For evaluation purposes, the IP addresses of devices that use Qantara.de apps will be logged; however, this happens anonymously. This anonymisation process is outsourced to a specialised service provider.

On principle, Qantara.de does not collect any data on location or device identification number (UDID). If personal data is to be collected and used within the framework of a Qantara.de app, this app will contain a separate declaration and information on data protection.

Qantara.de has no influence, however, on which data is collected and stored by network providers and operating system manufacturers when using its apps and how such data used.

**Which tools we use and how they work:**

**Facebook Pixel**

We use Facebook pixel to target people who visit Qantara.de's website more directly. As is common in this industry, we use Facebook Pixel to improve our advertisements and to provide people with more relevant ads.

Facebook pixel is a short piece of JavaScript code that is inserted into the HTML code of a web page. When a web page is loaded, Facebook pixel sends general information about the browser session to Facebook. If possible, a secure HTTP connection is used here. No personal data about the visitor to the website is transmitted.

For more information on [Facebook Data Policy and Settings](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation)

**AT Internet**

This service is used on all Qantara.de products as an analysis tool to improve our online content. Using [AT Internet](https://www.atinternet.com/en/company/data-protection/), we collect data on the number of page views and visits, on user behaviour and the length of time users spend on our online content. This data is gathered anonymously so no personal data is collected. We do not aggregate the collected data with other data sources.

If you do not agree to the tracking of your visit and want to prevent the collection of data by AT Internet, you can switch this off by referring to the [opt-out procedure ](https://www.xiti.com/en/optout.aspx)of the service provider.

**Internet services and social media integration (currently in development)**

Qantara.de continues to constantly test new services to support Internet-friendly ways of content distribution, including curating services such as ScribbleLive. We embed our content within social networks such as Facebook, Google Plus, Soundcloud, Twitter and YouTube.

For example, we embed content from providers such as YouTube, which is stored on their servers, on our websites. If you open a link to such a website that features outside content, this provider will receive the IP address of the device you use to go online. This external provider cannot draw any conclusions about your personal data from this IP address alone, but can infer, for example, where you are located geographically. Furthermore, this provider can program cookies on your device, with which they can log your online behavior.

Other examples are the embedded social network recommendation buttons (also called "social plugins") in our content.

**Modifications**

The information in this guide is intended to contribute to a better understanding of EU data protection rules. The guidelines will be updated regularly, content may be subject to modifications without notice.

_You can contact Qantara.de's data protection officer and data protection supervision at_

Qantara.de - Dialogue with the Islamic World

Deutsche Welle  
Kurt-Schumacher-Strasse 3  
53113 Bonn  
T. +49.228.429-0

datenschutz@dw.com

**Further reading:**

Facebook Data Policy and Settings

**Source URL:**[https://en.qantara.de/content/european-union-general-data-protection-reg...](https://en.qantara.de/content/european-union-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr-valid-may-25-2018)
